<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the Mayor, to the Alderman of the Ward of [blank] whereas divers good laws and ordinances have been made for the due observation of the Lord's Day : and divers penalties thereby imposed both upon the ...</title>
            <author>Corporation of London (England). Lord Mayor.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1654</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B09428</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing L2883G</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R179976</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">61297076</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 61297076</idno>
            <idno type="VID">180614</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B09428)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 180614)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2837:14)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the Mayor, to the Alderman of the Ward of [blank] whereas divers good laws and ordinances have been made for the due observation of the Lord's Day : and divers penalties thereby imposed both upon the ...</title>
                  <author>Corporation of London (England). Lord Mayor.</author>
                  <author>Vyner, Thomas, Sir, 1588-1665.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by James Flesher,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1654]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Form letter.</note>
                  <note>Place and date of publication suggested by Wing (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Title vignette: city of London coat of arms.</note>
                  <note>At the end: "Dated this 15th day of May, 1654."</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>London (England) --  History --  17th century.</term>
               <term>Sunday legislation --  England --  London --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Holidays --  Law and legislation --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Commonwealth and Protectorate, 1649-1660.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-07</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-08</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-08</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:180614:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>arms</figDesc>
               </figure>By the Mayor.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>
                  <hi>To the Alderman of the Ward of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                        <desc> _____ </desc>
                     </gap> 
                  </hi>
               </salute>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas divers good Laws and Ordinances have been made for the due obſervation of the Lords Day: And divers penalties thereby impoſed both upon the prophaners thereof, as alſo upon the Conſtables, Church<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wardens, Overſeers of the Poor, Parents, Maſters of Families and others, who ſhould by their neglect ſuffer the ſame. And albeit I have by ſeveral precepts, and otherwiſe, required all perſons concerned therein to perform their duties in that behalf, yet I have continuall complaint made unto me of a great neglect thereof, by ſuffering ſervants and children to play in the fields and ſtreets, and beggers to beg on that day. And to the intent that every one in their own particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar may be a Law unto themſelves in the obſerving of the Lords Day: And alſo that all perſons, who by the Law are appointed as inſtruments to prevent the propha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation thereof, and to bring to puniſhment ſuch as ſhall offend therein, may prevent the penalties to be inflicted upon them by the Law, Theſe are in the name of his Highneſſe the <hi>Lord Protector, of England, Scotland, and Ireland,</hi> to will and require you that preſently up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on ſight hereof you cauſe notice to be given to all the inhabitants within your Ward that they keep in their ſervants and children from playing in the fields and ſtreets on the Lords Day, as they will undergo the penalty in the ſaid Laws contained: And likewiſe that you cauſe notice to be given to all the Conſtables, Churchwardens, and Overſeers for the poor, that they within their ſeverall precincts take care to put the acts and ordinances in execution which are provided for the better obſervation of the Lords Day, to which they are ſeverally enjoyned upon a penalty of twenty ſhillings for every default therein. And alſo that the Conſtables within their ſeveral Precincts do prevent the ſinging of Ballads, which they are enjoyned to do under the penalty of forty ſhillings. And to the intent that all perſons may be without excuſe, you are to cauſe one of theſe precepts to be delivered to every Conſtable, Churchwarden, and Overſeer of the poor within your Ward, who are hereby required once every moneth to give me or ſome other Iuſtice of the Peace within the City and Liberties an exact ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compt of their doings herein, and not to fail as they will anſwer the contrary at their perill.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Dated</hi> 
                  <date>
                     <hi>this 15<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of May. 1654.</hi>
                  </date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>Sadler.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed by <hi>James Fleſher,</hi> Printer to the Honourable City of LONDON.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
